all right welcome to part three of
Master Camilla Sheena he was very famous
Indian Buddhist who lived about Stanley
780 750 750 ad so 1200 1300 years ago
and in ancient India that we still have
there are only two commentaries to the
diamond cutter Sutra Jim grunting and
one was by master Vasa blunder and it's
very short
it's kind of an outline and then the
other is by master Karuma less you know
and that one's quite long it's 130 pages
I think but it's very very difficult and
I'm not aware that anyone has taught it
since India I don't know 4000 years okay
that's right I just thought I would want
to read it and so I started reading it I
couldn't understand anything and then I
just kept working on it and another it's
pretty good and so my friends asked me
to share it with them and so I've been
sharing it he has some beautiful
meditations that you can do so I thought
it would be nice to learn it in a
retreat settings and so every morning
we'll we'll get up early and we'll come
down here and we'll do I don't know two
three hours of explanation and then
you'll go home and just do it okay and a
lot of people just finished a retreat
here long men retreat so you guys
already look very calm and now you're
going to get more calm and then you can
go back home and you'll be behind in
everything
and you can get nervous again so anyway
I really enjoy teaching it people have
been really teaching it around the world
John and Connie especially have been
teaching it a lot Michael and Melissa
and I appreciate that and I think it's
cool and so I you know start off me
caught it and I think it's cool who else
did a lot of talking so feel free to
teachings okay
and you know people can enjoy it so I
split it into four parts this is the
third part and we'll do the fourth part
next up October in at time a month okay
people ask me what I want to do after
that I said I always wanted to teach in
a gardener so we'll do that a year from
now okay all right now
I didn't finish part 2 I'd done a
mountain and I did some of it in Mexico
and I did some of it in Sedona and I did
some of it in New York but just for the
record I would like to finish part the
second part so we decided to have a
short closing ceremony in a short moment
chipper tonight and then add a class
tonight
so I know you're tired some of you've
been traveling a lot and I just want to
say I really like it that you're
exhausted and you have jet lag instead
of me and just imagine it was every week
like that okay so I'm going to cover a
few meditations from part two I'm
guessing we won't start parts made till
maybe tomorrow if we're lucky and I
think everyone has part two
[Music]
yeah make they have no there was a
abbreviated part to just a that I sent
him about three weeks ago huh okay do
you have the you have the file on you
want me give me the file so you can
project it okay come on
that's unfortunate I know I shouldn't
finish things ahead of time PDF or Word
file PDF okay bring me a flash drive
we'll get the reading to you tomorrow or
hope I hope also Stanley's been working
very hard on doing part three with the
whole Sutra so in four languages
Sanskrit Chinese Tibetan and English and
along with all the meditations so I'd
like to thank Stanley for that
[Applause]
and he says Catherine helped a lot thank
you for night Stanley has built about a
hundred translators in China pretty cool
this flashlight is not working sorry Hey
okay there you know it says come I said
something all right so the we're at a
part in the diamond cutter Sutra which
you will get this whole suit part 3 of
the Sutra in about three or four days
because I'm well let's say two three
days because I still have to do some
work on it I found some mistakes in the
Tibetan in the Sanskrit and soon so I'll
read you the Sutra it says and then the
Conqueror said suppose dosa beauty that
some son or daughter of noble family do
you guys know where we are
it's 41 piece number forty one if you
have the whole suit or you don't have
the whole suit or supports ability that
some son or daughter noble family were
to take all the planets of this great
world system a system with a thousand of
a thousand one thousand clinics and
covered them with the seven kind of
precious substances
not for them to someone suppose on the
other hand that anyone held but a single
verse of four lines from this particular
presentation of the Dharma and explained
it to others and taught it correctly by
doing the latter a person would create
many more great mountains of merit than
with the former the mountains of their
merit would be countless beyond all
calculations so he's saying suppose if
you covered a billion a billion planets
with gold and diamonds and offered it
even to the Buddha or you taught
somebody one verse from the diamond
color Sutra okay he says the teaching
would be infinitely greater good karma
okay so we're on that part and then the
meditation which is number nineteen this
tension from mountains to the body and
the bottom leads to Dharma buddy so you
guys know the Buddha has made it to put
it the most simple way has two bodies
one is their physical body and one is
there mental body and the emptiness of
them so the mental body and the
emptiness is called Dharma body
dharmakaya okay and commonly she'll have
some interesting thing you know he says
he's got a big connection between if you
teach Dharma you'll get the Dharma body
so he connects the two meanings of
Dharma okay
one is emptiness right Dharma body and
one is the teachings the Dharma and then
he draws a line between the traces if
you teach the Dhamma then it will act as
a cross for the Dharma body okay we
often sing our song based on the
gardener about this subject
nice living dictionary Gilardi at the
end of class we always quote this thing
based on the gardener's ratnamala string
of precious jewels and and we say by
this good karma may all beings complete
the collection of merit and wisdom
phrase and then normally merit good
karma creates your physical body of a
Buddha and wisdom creates the gaddama
body but how much it wants to push it
and he says when we teach drama you're
creating wisdom
so let's include it in the causes for
the Dharma body okay and and he knows
it's a little controversial he says I
don't care that's why I like him okay
then we had and we started combinational
number two with a section called the
aspiration for the physical body and we
talked about the Buddhist marks in
science and now we're on a section
called the aspiration to achieve the
Dharma body the mental of body and the
emptiness body of a Buddha okay and
generally speaking master commercial
divides the whole suture into 18 parts
and that's the part one now when he says
in the verse he said anyone who holds
the diamond cutter
anyone who explains it and anyone who
teaches it correctly so somebody comes
up to master karma student says what's
the difference and he's explained that a
couple of times and he changes his story
every time because he says all this
repetition in the diamond cutter Sutra
is on purpose and each time it has a
different meaning okay so for many
centuries people have wondered why the
Buddha repeated himself and magic Amla
Sheela always says it's no mistake he
didn't forget that he thought it already
I was in Singapore I told you the story
I talked to him at the trade union hall
- like 1200 people and then some guy not
Singaporean person and from a different
country from France came up and asked me
why did Jesus paid every time did you
forget you taught it last time I'm like
yeah maybe I forgot you know so so
Buddha never repeats themselves without
purpose right anyway when he says hold
the diamond cutter common-law Sheila
says it means memorize pieces of it you
know and be able to recite them okay so
you don't have to try to memorize the
whole diamond cutter it's long it's 40
pages in the Tibetan and Sanskrit but
you can memorize some cool parts okay
it's good my friend today gave me a
little bucket for washing my feet and
recited some chicken things and that's
good okay so James a part that you like
and learn it learn to recite it it's
much better to teach it from your memory
okay then he says then what does it mean
to explain the diamond cutter Sutra and
he says oh the word explain means the
words explain the meaning of the words
like what's the Sanskrit word mean what
are the roots of the Sanskrit word what
other pieces of it and you know Tibetan
explain what the Tibetan words mean I
enjoy that kind of thing right and it's
a tradition in Buddhism so the second
thing you do is explain the word Deen
but not the meaning of the thing just
the worst so make sure the student
appreciates all the different flavors of
each one then finally he
said peach correctly unfortunately the
word correctly was in there
you only get these mountains a good car
if you teach it correctly but I think it
could be pretty much correct me in in
our case right and he says when British
had teach correctly then he's talking
about teaching the meaning of the
diamond cutter Sutra okay hold four
lines explained the wording and then
teach the meaning and then you've taught
the diamond cutter and that's a direct
that is the direct cost for the body of
a Buddha the mind of a Buddha okay all
right there's a more expanded list later
on and Camilla Sheila where he explains
that and it has ten parts so here's ten
different ways of teach or things
involved was passing on the diamond Kama
Sutra okay number one just causing it to
be printed or writing at the copying it
you know the first time I taught in
Mongolia I think a thousand people came
and we gave our diamond cutter suture to
every person and it was fun and we had
repented them then the first day I got
there I got like fifty Mongolian women
and they all sewed book gloss each one
did twenty book gloss and we gave a
suture to each person who came for free
so that's a reproducing the suitor
number one number two helping to support
that spreading the diamond cutter
financially helping to support it
through giving the teachings yourself
like John and Connie or who else but
then
gentles been doing number four just
reading the citrus that's it you can
read it over and over and each time you
see something new okay number five
listening to it
number six memorizing it
number seven getting low low means you
just read it out loud to your friends as
a transmission or all transmissions
number eight just reciting it every day
a lot of Chinese people recite that can
continue every day that's a good custom
number nine number nine is ready just
lay down in your bed and you think about
it you read one page and then you just
think about it not necessarily lay down
okay
you can think about it sitting up also
remember ten meditating about it these
are ten ways you can relate to the
diamond color then come by Sheila goes
further and says if you really want to
master the diamond cutter secret you
should come to as many teachings as you
can on all Buddhist subjects like along
em okay if you really want to understand
the the diamond cutter you should come
to many teachings as many as you can
okay and he calls it widespread learning
and then he said the habit of widespread
learning causes the widespread side of
the teachings which is yeah but it's
such a mentality buddy Tunis
I want to save the world like DC ID I
mean the goal is really to change the
world you know we'll go around the world
endlessly cuz we want to change the room
the whole world
then just for your information
every time he finishes a section one
important idea
he will classify it he'll say this is
the profound side or this is the
widespread size profound side means was
yet this verse or this section of the
diamond cutter is talking about
emptiness mostly and then he'll say no
this part is talking about body starts
activities which are global or multi
global okay and this this quotation he
calls widespread this has to do with
bodhichitta okay also at the end of
every section in his commentary he will
say that this section relates to this
part of cebu d's question the question
that started the sutra okay so this
sutra starts out with a question the
question has three parts tell me any
part how should we live how should we
think and how should we yeah how should
we live how should we practice and how
should we think though that was the
question that began the sutra and the
whole sutra is an answer to that
question so everytime buddha says
something else
kamila sheila likes to say oh he's
answering this part of the question he's
answering that part of the question you
see one of the three parts of the
question what's that well i'll remind
you what buddha shortened to us to the
three question how should we live means
we should live in hope that we can
achieve the qualities of a Buddha and we
can get rid of our negative quality
that's how to live live in hope second
one was how should we practice
and he said focus on your practice
concentrate your practice especially on
Antonis and then sibility said well how
how should we focus and Buddha says
focus on emptiness in your interactions
with other people and don't get
distracted by yes the Gotcha on the
second husband don't get distracted by
things that seem to be coming from
themselves like when your partner
criticizes you okay like when your your
partner's very close to you you live
with them all the time you're very
linked in with each other and then when
one criticizes the other you get
especially hurt it feels especially bad
and then it would be easy in those
moments to be distracted Yama is the
classical Fault in meditation is to
think about a hamburger when you're
trying to concentrate on your Lamas face
okay so but in in the diamond cutter
future distraction means you slip and
you think your partner is coming from
their side okay you forget that they are
criticizing you because you criticize
somebody last week okay so that's what
distraction means in the diamond cutter
Sutra distraction during meditation
means slipping with your partner at home
in the kitchen when they criticize you
okay that's just that's distraction not
not falling for that focusing is the
answer to the third question what was
the third question
yeah how should we focus right how
should we think and in the answer is
just remember that things are coming
from you that's how you should think the
answer to the second question was learn
about how things are coming from your
emptiness and the answer to the third
question is when you get in a tight
situation emotional situation your
husband criticizes you very strongly
then remember don't get distracted don't
forget okay that's good a short answer
the Sutra is a long answer okay and as I
said master karma see the likes to
connect every section of the sutra two
to one third of the answer isa so this
section is about your husband or this
section is about learning emptiness okay
this this section is about hope for the
future okay and he splits up the diamond
cutter in a certain way and I have
followed it so and I put a reference
number on each part so the Bible the
Christian Bible was around for a long
time the New Testament three books
synoptic Gospels plus John's and this
preacher horse riding around on a horse
in New England and I don't know 1700
1800 he put numbers on them so when he
went to different farms people could
remember which one he talked about so
this is a mark 3 verse 12 things like
that so it's very helpful so I did it in
the in the three treasures prayer book
so even if they're doing it in Spanish
or Chinese or English you can see where
we are and I did it for the diamond
kamasutra okay so we're following the
numbers of common lasheeda
okay so if you want to talk to your
friends you could say let's talk about
part 78 we absolutely beyond par 44
right now I think okay
by the way the third answer which was
when I'm just checking your retention
yeah stay focused okay what do we call
it is in a moment of tension with your
partners
you remember that they're coming from
you
it's taking refuge that's the real
meaning in Buddhism protection it
protects you then you don't tell your
husband he's stupid even if he is and
then you don't have to hear him call you
stupid again because you stopped and you
protected yourself okay so that's refuge
we just finished you know we've been
studying refuge in the alarm room for
months okay okay all right I'm giving
you a summary of commerce Sheila's
comments and don't forget they all
relate to this one meditation you know
you are going to teach the diamond
cutter Sutra each person in this room is
going to teach the diamond cutter Sutra
it might be in your friends kitchens
when their husband comes in it says
something bad you can teach it very
quickly the diamond cutter Sutra and
they won't say something bad to their
husbands or it might be in front of I
don't know necklace just in front of 500
600 people in Xiamen teaching them this
stuff okay let's get on it no just
kidding so maybe you're teaching
somebody in their kitchen and maybe
you're teaching 600 people are you know
it's up to you but you should all teach
that's the meaning of the first
meditation so when they do this
meditation this will be the first
meditation you do tomorrow think about
how how could I share this thing right
not not preach don't tell people but
share right don't bother people on the
plane home
don't tell the person back to you about
the diamond cutter Sutra if they want to
sleep okay now next thing calmly Sheila
says this by the way not only is that
the most powerful Karma to teach the
diamond cutters and not only does that
climber create the Dharma body of a
Buddha quickly but it also has an effect
on your negative sees right like if you
made mistakes in the past
and you want to diffuse them
short-circuit them teach the diamond
cutters to people and the good karma
will deactivate the bad karma
okay so there's an effect on your
negative seeds also all right
then there in the next section you know
somebody says to Buddha oh really
the Karma's dad Pig you know just one
verse taught poorly in my house to
somebody it's more good karma and
covering a billion planets with gold and
offering to Buddhist then in the next
section but is it I'm not exaggerating
okay I'm not you know just trying to
impress you
it's it's actually true because if the
result is the Dharma body the cause must
be unbelievable it must be beyond
imagination okay if you can create the
highest thing in the universe with it
with a karma it's got to be the coolest
comment warm sharing sharing emptiness
with another person teaching legend
country so he says I wasn't exaggerating
because the result of look at the result
of that karma is it makes you a Buddha
to give you a Dharma body then it must
be the best commentary he runs it
backwards got it
all right just not if you don't okay
then somebody starts complaining him you
know really making good karma certain
Amir she told ocean center mission
determined uh McLean temperature right
the cause of the cause of the physical
body of the Buddha is collecting good
karma if you make good karma from
teaching Dharma it should cause the
physical bodies were then Commission
says no and the person says Wyatt and he
says well first of all you're teaching
Dharma so you're getting done dharmakaya
duh okay like he makes sort of a cool
connection okay then he says the result
of teaching is everyone gets more wisdom
and that's the classical cause of the
Dharmakaya okay then he says by the way
who would think that the physical body
of a Buddha is the Buddha it's not it's
the part that thinking is the Buddha got
it okay the mind of the buddha is the
real Buddha he said the rest is just a
reflection you know when you talk to
somebody would you rather have their
body or their minds
I mean I accept your husband okay
he's like don't listen to you anyway I
just mean you know if that body didn't
have a mind you could talk to it for all
day and it wouldn't answer you right but
if you had the mind without the body you
can text them you see you don't have the
bodies not next to you but you can text
them he says of course the the main part
of Buddhist to mind of the buddha dhamma
Kai
okay got it all right dude somebody says
but wait a minute diamond diamond
diamond beads everything I mean what's
that sick shame what's the shaming
what's the six-year Dharma yeah what's
the entomological yeah the rudest birth
Berman's to hold and in the definition
of a Dharma etymological is anything
which holds its own essence rugged modes
in viña sure anything that holds its own
nature is there anything that does its
own nature's term
Dharma okay what are some English
cognate true tree through big truths
here through it okay these are the
classical cognitive birth okay it
meaning firm like a tree you know can't
shake it
okay true true comes from the tree comes
from dirt okay all right so they
complain to him it's as well
everything's Dharma and the whole Buddha
must be done micaiah
he said yeah yeah that's not we're
talking about okay now if somebody comes
up to a combination and says wait a
minute you know you said ultimately
speaking there's no Dharma I already
said in the Sutra and ultimately
speaking there's no enlightenment
there's no Buddhahood now how can there
be a connection between the two
how can I collect karma that makes me a
Buddha if there's no Buddha and there's
no Dumber how could I teach Dharma which
doesn't exist and that's going to make
me a Buddha that doesn't exist how can
there be any connection between two
zeros you know okay somebody's
complaining like that so we're going to
go to the idea of mish kaya say miss
kaya this a hard hard Sanskrit word in
in the income unless you know and you
don't see it anyplace else
biscaia means you ready I call it
disembodied karma triggers I liked it I
think it's sexy
okay get him bodied Karma triggers okay
niche means not kaya means body okay so
by the way I could have been like six
different words I chose Mishka I don't
have the sense could have come with you
that's missing somebody found it
recently and I got all excited I was
with dr. Wu and we were in Sedona and I
said one of my students Thomas come
unless you know yeah we're all excited
then we read the first page carefully
and it said I translated this from the
Tibetan back back to some obscure I just
threw it out I said throw it out they
said no no I said I just turn out it's
okay okay
anyway he talks about how can teach it
Dharma the karma trigger the Dharma body
okay it if they are both disembodied
okay what's that mean
there's no substance to them okay how
can in action trigger a part of the
Buddha if they never touch each other
okay do the cause and the result exists
at the same time they cannot cause comes
first you teach Dhamma in Guangzhou you
teach engaging in Guangzhou caramel
asana you bring it back to China okay
and then you know next year you have a
Dharma body you can come and show us
okay look I got Dharma bargaining here
and but that's next year you see by the
time you the diamond bodies there you
finish teaching all right when you're
teaching the body is not there yet they
come at different times so by the time
you have the body the teaching is City
and gone and while you're teaching the
body is not there yet so how can
something that's not there because by
something which is there and how can
something which is not there anymore
teaching cause something which is there
they should exist at the same time if I
tickle the you know then her side and my
finger has to be at the same time you
see otherwise you can't tickle somebody
so house they're causing the same the
teaching is God by the time you have to
buy they're not exist there's no contact
they are disembody they're both not real
they don't touch they never touch each
other the cause never touches the result
ever nothing then okay that's what this
means
what's the other thing they're the
intimus of the space between the trigger
and the result okay there's a space
between the trigger and the result okay
there has to be a time gun the teaching
finishes and then you get a Dharma body
later by timing at the Dharma body to
teach is not there but it's tickling
that Dharma body
but it doesn't exist I think is that's a
proof that it's coming from your mind
that's a proof that things are coming
from your mind okay got it it doesn't
exist out there this way
teaching and body and their connection
cannot exist out there it must be coming
from you who makes the connection
between teaching and getting Buddha body
is you it's coming from you okay who
made causation I should wear my t-shirt
right in in call Engel who made the
connection you make the cut it's so cool
you make the connection okay we make the
teaching concert on body
okay the teaching didn't teaching didn't
give you of phish tahko
teaching didn't get you some fish to it
I mean there's a connection
teaching is kindness getting a Dharma
body is the result of kindness who made
the connection we did it's very cool
okay that's what he's talking about it's
very difficult it's very difficult
who said that teaching should give you a
body dhamma body and not a yo child who
said that who decided yeah who decided
the laws of karma you did you mean they
could be different yeah they could be
crazy they could be crazy you could do
nice things to people and get shot or
something or you could shoot people and
have people say you're a great man make
movies about you you see it would be
crazy you made the connection you made
dependent origination got it cool if
you're going to study
DCI the answer to everything is four
steps okay
if you're gonna study diamond cutter
whatever somebody says you say oh yeah
it's coming from me okay say the answers
are the punch line is always the same
okay the punch line is so always the
same
that's a booty halfway to the citrus
starts crying he says this is goddamn
amazing you know anytime anybody asks
you a question you always twist it
around to emptiness you know there's a
whole Sutra there's not a single word in
the Sutra that you don't start teaching
emptiness you know he's so amazing
Buddha and he starts to cry so I call
this course arias tears okay it's
there's a there's a verse where he just
starts to cry he says you didn't say a
single normal word in this Sutra then
somebody came to accomplish he said no
there is a normal word in the Sutra he
said what he says
the Buddha says morning in the morning
then cobbler Sheila writes a three-page
explanation of why that's emptiness and
I'm going to teach you it's so sexy me
and Veronica are talking about it it's
cool we'll do that later okay that'll be
like Wednesday something okay anyways so
really this is about how things cannot
touch each other okay and I remember in
my three day routine I gave a talk
I don't know if you remember but when
you look at when you're in diamond
mountain retreat Valley tomorrow morning
and you get up and you see the dawn come
up and you see the Sun come over the
mountain where it's a line that
separates the mountain from the Sun you
see where does the sunlight touch the
mountain where does the mountain stop
and the Sun begins
and you can't find that place okay you
can say there must be one atom touching
one atom if you could use a microscope
and the Sun and the in the mountain
where do they touch you will never find
a place there's no such a place you see
and cause and result they never touch
okay you you think there must be a place
where there's an atom of light and
there's an atom of mountain and that the
left side of the light atom is touching
the right side of the mountain atom
that's where the touch but that's not
possible it's a single plane it is no
width to it it can't be a space shared
between two atoms it's not possible
there's no such thing in math if you ask
your teacher what's the point you know
and they say here take your pencil make
a point and then they say but it's not
really a point because the point has no
winds right
there's no such thing got it okay then
when you look when the wind touches some
reason and Musa leaves we sometimes we
have small winds here by the way it's
very rare it only happens when people
come here from Germany and stuff like
that so what makes the leaf move you
know in the tree where does the wind
touch to leave you can't find it you
really can't find it that's post that is
coming from your mind okay the wind is
not touching to me okay and we're going
to talk about in when we start coming
here three probably getting late right
probably the day after tomorrow Buddha
goes into the connection between tiny
things and galactic things in science
it's called quantum theory as opposed to
the general theory of gravity or
relativity in science they studied big
things to understand small things and
they study small things to understand
big things and but it did it two and a
half thousand years ago and it's in the
diamond cutter Sutra okay we study how
the atoms work so we understand how
planets work and we watched I don't know
the bending of light around mercury to
understand how atoms work okay
all right by the way I've also been
studying The Wheel of Life commentary
but vasa blunder right I told you that
and it's very long it's hundreds of
pages and as I said in the abhidharma
culture closure which is the most famous
book by Massimo nahi it's a long dry
book about you know 18 divisions there's
and 81 divisions of distance and then in
his will of life book you see him hit
the real bus abundant any funny and it's
brilliant and its controversial and it's
cool it's like a different person you
know totally different person but in
that book he says how about hell you
think link number one causes link number
two how can not understanding Kong Xin
make Karma where did they touch they
don't link number one doesn't cause link
number 2 London link number 2 dozen cars
link number 3 numbers he didn't cause me
number 4 he goes into a long story they
never touched okay how could they
[Music]
okay all right
mmm you by the way in your meditation so
I think we're gonna hit one meditation
but to this
you might think about okay there are the
four laws of common right according to
this idea you created them okay
karma in your world is consistent what's
the first law of karma
she caught Mexico you know if you're
nice to people you'll get good things if
you hurt people get bad things who made
that
who made that law you see or does that
just exist if the world runs that way or
did you make it you know I made it it's
very interesting how you think about it
you know in this meditation think about
it okay who made consistency who created
cause-and-effect why is it true if you
hurt somebody you get something bad you
you think about it I'll give you a clue
it's consistent okay and it's rational
you hurt you get hurt you give you get
money right you stay loyal to your
partner you keep your partner's you see
I mean okay all right you know go deeper
you don't want to go to the second
meditation from last time all right
I'll just throw another thing at you
okay you can think about it I mean if
you understood where Karma's coming from
that would be a big thing right who made
who wrote the law of karma I do before I
knew about it he says come unless Sheela
asked this question he goes deeper you
ready
by the way this is karma show three it's
not common less evil one
okay it's not DCI I get to go as deep as
I want I'm in Diamond Mountain
I get to wear robes okay I get to be a
Buddhist for a couple weeks okay
and I don't care if you don't understand
okay you should go back to college
you're number one round three these are
the tough people okay
he says how do we distinguish between
the act of enlightenment and the person
who gets enlightened what's the
difference between getting enlightened
and being a knight or being the person
who gets enlightened okay how do you
recognize that you're a buna I'll ask
you a question be careful don't forget
common lishchyna - if you see the 112
sides on your body that only a Buddha
has do you know your Buddha so booty
said no no way okay got it
just because you have the signs on your
body that only Buddha's have doesn't
mean you're a Buddha why someone has to
glued together
someone has to glue it together okay you
can have a wheel and a steering wheel
and a window and four doors and it's not
a car it's just pieces of a car your
mind has to make a car out of the pieces
people with what do you call that
Alzheimer's when I forget the word
permanently all habit they they can't
glue things together anymore okay they
see like a sock and they see a shoe and
they don't connect them you know in so
are the parts of a car car
no one more one more part is necessary
one more part is always necessary
the part that glues them together and
that's the karmic seed get open in your
mind and a picture came out how did you
get that seed you gave people rides to
Tucson airports well you helped people
get from the temple to their cabin okay
many times and you made a car a car from
that from pieces of a car
who made the pieces well that's another
story okay but the pieces of a car are
not a car until karma opens in your mind
and a picture comes out and puts them
all together and then you can join it
okay that karma is getting other people
help to go someplace like pay for the
translators trip to dime moment
something the airplane okay that makes
car works got it we want to go deeper
therefore what the building blocks of
all things is not atoms its kindness
it's helping other people okay you are
not atomists you are commerce okay okay
got it all right Adam yes who put them
together you did why you were nice to
other people okay okay that's the real
building block of reality okay all right
Marty
[Music]
by the way last thing Carmen Sheila says
about this idea our number to write
about the disembodied karmic trigger no
we're not we're still on disembodied
commentary I know it's frustrating go
back yeah there you go
the last thing he says about this is
that so the secret started out with how
to be a bodhisattva and the first
perfection of a bodhisattva is giving
okay like the city started out with a
discussion of giving and then we said
there's two kinds of giving okay one
kind of giving results in things you get
money you give money you get money you
help other people make money you get
money okay and I'll tell you something
cool you meditate about it okay I'm it's
not simple you have to write down what
I'm saying if you don't write down what
I'm saying you're gonna go to your cabin
and say what am I supposed to do okay
everything that I'm talking about you're
supposed to think about it okay here's a
cool one okay if you understand those
gaps between cause and effect when you
give things to other people
it never ends the result never ends I'll
say it again if you understand how
something which never touches another
thing can still cause it
then when you give things the wealth you
get back will be a bit of paradise
unending well unending happiness okay
unending beauty okay and if you don't
understand that gap okay if you just
ignore it if you say guess I don't
really care
let me just give people rides and I'll
get a mercedes-benz even in Singapore or
Hong Kong where it costs five times
every place else
okay just teach me how to do that I
don't care about the Howard causes I
don't need to know okay if you don't
want to know that car will end that car
will break down somebody will steal it
okay it will break down
okay got it if you worry about how can
teaching Dharma created Dharma body if
they never touch each other if you worry
about that in your meditation at Diamond
then when you give people money it will
come back forever
it's different okay the first one is
called samsara suffering life the second
one is called paradise heaven
okay now you meditate about it worry
about that okay so I said if I
understand those gaps money will come
back forever if you said I don't
understand the gathers just come back
once and then caused me trouble I don't
understand that's why you're dreaming
okay you're supposed to worry about it
in retreat and because you're quiet and
you're not going to talk out to the
night by the way you can talk in the
class you can ask questions if you
decide to talk to somebody and they
decide to talk back to you that's your
business you are adults I'm not gonna
you know sneak into your house and see
if you're talking although maybe I will
but you won't have a good retreat
you won't understand these karmic
triggers and you'll go home the same and
you wasted your effort okay it's up to
you if you want to have a good time
don't talk if you want to have a bad
time use your cell phone if you want to
waste the whole trip use your cell phone
okay I don't I can't you know my cell
phone usage place is secret nobody can
go in there except em sometimes the
squirrel comes in there to watch me poop
oh I don't know why but you know it's up
to you you want to have a good retreat
these strings okay if you don't want to
have a good routine if you want to waste
your money waste your time waste my time
then bla bla we can't okay
we used to take away people's cell
phones then I lost one and I had to pay
for and I stopped doing it okay anyway
some people are - okay we have 15 more
minutes okay
we're going to do one more
[Music]
okay.come ratio divides the diamond
cutter cetera into 18 parts we reach the
fifth one okay we reach the fifth one
the fifth one is called don't have
delusions about your practice okay
don't have wrong ideas about your own
success in meditation okay it's a very
subtle section okay if you have a little
success in your meditation don't get up
hamana hamana hamana means I found a
cool translation what was it hyper mind
hi / / mind okay don't get all excited
ah now I'm and I yeah the minute you
think I'm an aria you become a uhnari oh
okay it's very subtle the moment you
have certain ideas about your own
spiritual success you mess it up okay
it doesn't mean you can't be happy you
should be happy if your husband yelled
at you the day you get back from this
retreat and you remember this between
and you don't say anything you just took
refuge and there Jeet was a success for
you even if you get angry the next day
okay you had a good retreat okay you
stopped 1 comma C okay that's okay so
this one is very subtle like how to have
a proper attitude when you get someplace
cool in your meditation huh not avoid
this big mind big mine what's big mine
you think it's coming from you I'm sorry
from its side
okay because you got excited you forgot
it's coming from helping other people
okay all right so that's the section
we're on you know like understanding it
when you have success in your practice
okay here's the quotation from the Sutra
now it's a booty what do you think when
people enter the stream do they think to
themselves I did it I entered the stream
and then it's called a panna cotta pata
I entered the stream okay throw as Sr
comes in the English as FL don't ask me
why what is it slow okay stream enter
okay so stream enter is a nickname for
someone who just saw emptiness directly
okay you enter the stream I always like
to compare it to Jackie Chan in what
movie the myth you know and he and this
bad guy are fighting in a glue factory
and there's a conveyor belt and he gets
stuck on the conveyor belt and his
girlfriend his Indian girlfriend gets
stuck on the conveyor belt and she's
gonna die when the she get to the
chopper anyway that's a perfect image
for stream entering okay it's a it's a
conveyor belt when you see into this
directly you'll get glued to a thing
that's moving to enlightenment nothing
can stop you and it's within a certain
amount of time okay that's it you made
it stream you're going to reach the
ocean like in two days
stream enters okay throat
but okay okay now Buddha says to sebou
tea if someone reaches three mentor they
just saw emptiness directly okay do they
think of themselves
I'm stream enter and yeah no they don't
okay well what's that mean
so I I put a picture of a lady she
entered the stream and she's trying to
help you get into it also okay it says
no mood during know me after or I would
lose it okay so here's a question for
you while you're seeing emptiness
directly if penny is is in meditation
because he used his meditation app that
he's writing for DCI he has his writing
a cool meditation African let's say he
used it he tested it himself
and then he saw emptiness directly
because of his meditation app which may
have something to do with helping
hundreds of thousands of other people
meditate let's say he sees emptiness
okay so he's inside the direct
perception emptiness for like twenty
minutes okay after zillions of lifetimes
can he think to himself I did it why not
because penny is not coaching and during
those twenty minutes you are swimming
inside function you can't see anything
else if penny saw penny while he was in
comforting it would spit him out of
course you okay it's very interesting
it's a get out penny
you just thought about yourself look
okay then you couldn't stay inside
okay so during stream enter the first
part look series like stream enter
during the first part seeing arguments
directly
penny cannot think about penny okay all
right if he thinks I did it he spit out
of emptiness because he's not emptiness
he emptiness if you want to say simple
way emptiness is negative
Kenny's positive okay emptiness is
something missing ten days and
something's here penny cannot be
emptiness if penny started thing about
penny in the middle of emptiness he will
lose emptiness okay
also Penny's changing every second
emptiness never changes okay so they're
incompatible got it now a big question
is when he comes out of the stream he
still we call him now he's an
established stream entering okay then
does he think about penny he does okay
does he think about penny the way he
used to
that's delicate question okay we say
when he comes out and he thinks about
penny he's still thinking about penny
the wrong way okay until he's a nut
heart that's a difference okay but he
knows he's thinking the wrong way okay
okay he came out of emptiness they just
I think Oh penny did it I do you know
then he's just over Penny's not when I
saw penny was now I still see penny as
penny but I know Penny's not what I
thought it was maybe I'll try to get our
hearts then I won't think about penny
wrong way anymore okay so still he
doesn't seem 100% wrong way anymore but
ninety percent wrong okay I'm sorry
penny then you have to make another out
okay then somebody comes up to Buddha
okay common luckily says look
carmella Sheila get real do you know
this idiom it means stop being anyway
you know get real means you know try to
understand something okay
get real man get real
so Buddha never said in my former life
when I was King surah Dada I did this
and that's why I'm a Buddha now because
if if , Sheila says yes Buddha did say
in his former life he was Kings for the
data and he did this and it helped him
become a Buddha if he says I was King
sir Dada then it's the same as your
booty sufferer who says I'm a
bodhisattva or the stream mandarin says
I'm assuming they didn't kick out a
Buddhahood also it Buddha says I was
formalised King sir about that which he
said in a Sutra which suture look to the
Samadhi Roger okay which is a favorite
Souter of communist healer because it's
a source of meditation okay in that's
why I mention it in that Sutra Buddha
told the story of his former life as
Kings her Dada and he says I was Kings
her daughter and the other guy says wait
a minute if stream and says I'm stream
and he's not a streamer if Buddha say I
am King said daughter before then he's
not blue okay Amy
that's Buddha when Buddha talks about
himself does put it up answer yes I used
to be this King and I did this thing and
I became a Buddha okay so you can of
Bodhisattva talk about themselves yes
canna stream enters say I'm a stream
winter
if not then British shouldn't talk about
his former life that's the point okay
if it's wrong then why did Buddha do it
if it's wrong to talk about yourself
because you will misunderstand yourself
then why did wouldn't talk about he was
king sir doctor in the past life yeah it
seemed wrong it's Butera there must be a
good way of talking about yourself and a
bad way of talking myself you meditate
on it I'm not going to tell you the
answer but I am going to tell you the
story because I think it's cool I went
and got it for you from the Samadhi Raja
certificate this is the story of King
Cyrus okay and I'll make it short okay
there was a large group of Bodhisattvas
practicing in an empty place very
similar to Diamond Mountain and one of
them was named su Pushpa Chandra and
they all made a promise to each other
they will stay out in the empty land
away from the city and they will
meditate they will do retrieve they will
try to see emptiness okay they made a
deal with each other we will do a long
retreat we will stay here in Diamond
Mountain empty place final one year and
three years but they made a deal to stay
together in the empty place and do
between okay then one whose name's sue
Pushpa Chandra which means a beautiful
moon like a flower okay
he in his meditation he saw if I go back
to the cities if I leaved I'm mom and I
go back to Singapore or I go back to
Beijing or I go back to Guangzhou okay
and I teach people they have a chance
real chance to reach brutally because of
what I understood in my retreat if I
leave the retreat and I share with
people in my city in the city then
there's a good chance they will become
Buddha okay so he told his he told his
friends I'm going to the city then they
said you promised to stay here you know
now you want to go you know and when you
get to the city those city people going
to change you you're not going to change
the city people they're going to change
you you know you start getting
interested in cars and girls and bars
and malls and you know they're going to
change you okay then he went to the city
and what was that III forgot the story
but I think he stood outside the king's
palace for many days and everybody
ignored him and then some cool things
happened and he started teaching people
and many of them saw emptiness and in a
thousand and then five thousand and then
ten thousand people start come to his
teaching and they see emptiness okay
then the King got jealous okay sort of
doctor the King got jealous because he
became popular with his queens also then
he told his soldiers to kill him you
know and they took him and they cut off
his arms and legs and they dug out his
eyes okay and they threw the parts of
him in different places
and it suddenly all the parts to start
making light like the Sun you know his
leg is making light over there his arm
is making liner in the
and then that you could start to see the
signs of buddha on those parts you know
you know now became clear he has this
part then that King said oops I made
booboo okay and also he saw that after
week the parts are still there making
light you know then he so I made a
mistake you know then he heard a voice
from the sky it said you are going then
then he he decided here become Buddhist
and he started to practice very hard and
I guess what happened to him in the
later life he became our Buddha
Sakyamuni okay that was our Buddha
former life okay so Buddha always ends
the story he says don't think it was
somebody else it was me who made this
mistake it was my fault I did the
mistake okay so anyway if the Buddha
talked that long in the Samadhi roots at
Rajasuya about himself and a stream
enter talk about himself
then how come Buddha doesn't get kicked
out of Buddhahood that's a question okay
you have to think about it we're almost
finished three minutes
Master Commission has a nice explanation
of tumblr which Chungnam path of seeing
darshana Marga ok darshana market Najma
means passing Marga means pan-russian
and manga okay and he says once you see
emptiness directly the city of Nirvana
is in sight I just thought it's kind of
cool
normally we see we say it means what
seeing emptiness directly but he says it
can also you can say now the time before
you reached Nirvana or Buddhahood is is
fixed 500 years then you can see the end
you know then that's path of see okay he
explains it that way I'm going to do the
rest tomorrow because it's kind of
difficult and it's not a good thing to
do it at night when you just travel okay
okay it kind of it's a long proof of why
why it's wrong to say I achieve stream
enter okay we'll talk about it tomorrow
I think we won't even get to come was
here three
how many we finished there on the third
one I think that's okay